Shri Ganesha Gauri Puja, Sydney, Australia, April 4, 1981
澳洲雪梨 聖女哥維(象神格泥沙的母親)崇拜，1981 年 4 月 4 日
Today is a very unique thing that is happened,
今天發生了一件非常獨特的事情，
is a special luck for Sahaja yogis of Australia.
對於澳洲的霎哈嘉瑜珈士來說，這是一個特別的幸運日。
This day has never been celebrated before
在霎哈嘉瑜伽的歷史上，
in the history of Sahaja Yoga.
這一天從未被慶祝過。
Today is the New Year’s Day for Sahaja yogis,
今天是霎哈嘉瑜伽士的新年，
because this is the New Year’s Day
因為今天是
of the Shalivahan calendar.
沙利瓦漢曆的新年。
As you know, Shalivahan is My dynasty,
如你們所知，沙利瓦漢是我的王朝，
and they are called as Shalivahan
他們被稱為沙利瓦漢，
because they are the carriers of the shawls of the Goddess,
因為他們是女神披肩的攜載者，
they are called as the, because as you are also carrying
他們被稱為沙利瓦漢，因為——就像你們也多次
so many times My shawls around.
攜帶我的披肩一樣——
And they were called as Shalivahan.
他們被稱為沙利瓦漢。
So this New Year’s Day is the first day of advent of Goddess,
所以，沙利瓦漢新年的元旦是女神降臨的第一天──
the nine days there are.
總共有為期九天的慶典。
Then in another times that there are Satya Yug,
之後還有善世（Satya Yuga）、
then there’s Dvapara, Treta, Kali Yuga: there are four yugas.
青銅時代（Dvapara Yuga）、三分時代（Treta Yuga）和爭鬥時代（Kali Yuga）：共有四個時代。
So in two yugas the Goddess incarnated,
女神在兩個時代降世，
one before the Satya Yuga and one after it.
一個在善世之前，一個在善世之後。
So today is the day to mark absolutely the first day
所以今天是她降生於世
when She incarnated on this Earth.
的第一天。
That’s the day also of the Gauri,
今天也是哥維女神（Gauri）的日子，
because Virgin is the first form of the Goddess.
因為聖女是女神的第一種形態。
And She created also Ganesha on Tuesday,
她還在本週的星期二
just starting this week.
創造了象神格泥沙（Ganesha）。
What is the day? The day today is …?
今天是星期幾?今天是...?
[Today’s the fourth.]
[今天是四號。]
Today ….
今天…..
[Saturday, Mother.]
[星期六，母親。]
[Saturday.]
[星期六。]
Saturday. Now, now, it’s over. Now don’t stay, all right?
星期六。好了，好了，結束了。別再待在這裡了，好嗎？
While I’m speaking you should not take My photographs.
我說話的時候你們不要拍照。
It’s a very wrong idea, because it disturbs Me.
這樣不好，會打擾我。
Moreover, you see, when the speaking, while I’m speaking
而且，你們看，我說話的時候，你們拍照，
and when you take My photograph
而你們卻拍照的話
sometimes I’ve seen they come out very odd.
有時候拍出來的照片很奇怪。
Best take photographs when I’m not speaking, you see,
最好在我沒說話的時候拍照，
because all the time the sound is coming, everybody is distracted
因為我說話的時候，相機的聲音會讓大家分心，
and the attention doesn’t fix, you see.
注意力就無法集中，你懂吧。
Is a very important thing I’m talking, all right?
我現在說的是非常重要的事，好嗎？
Now don’t take any photographs, please.
先請不要拍攝任何照片。
Pay attention to what I’m saying.
認真聽我說。
[Hindi]
[印地語]
So Tuesday is the day when Ganesha was established,
星期二是向象神格泥沙誕生的日子，
and then the Goddess started working.
然後女神開始工作。
The first one, the one day when She started is, was the Wednesday.
她真正開始工作的日子是星期三。
She started working out on Wednesday.
她從星期三開始行動。
Wednesday is the action day,
星期三是行動日。
that’s why she started on Wednesday.
這就是她為何選擇星期三開始的原因。
Today is, under the circumstances it is Saturday;
在目前的情況下，今天是星期六；
but I’m telling you about the original timings.
但我說的是原本的時間。
Because Wednesday is the day of the Swadisthana,
因為星期三正是腹輪日，
that’s the day She started working it out, the whole thing.
也就是她開始工作的日子，一切都從那天開始。
So first, Tuesday is the first day in Sahaja Yoga,
首先，在霎哈嘉瑜伽中，星期二是第一天，
Wednesday is the second day.
星期三是第二天。
And you’ll be surprised that the stars are also the same,
你會驚訝地發現，星像也是如此排列。
because Tuesday is the day of the Mars
因為星期二是火星之日
which is resided by Shri Ganesh.
而火星是象神格泥沙的居所。
Wednesday is the day of Mercury, and Mercury is the Swadisthana.
星期三是水星日，而水星代表腹輪
Third day – yes – third day is the day of Jupiter:
第三天——沒錯——第三天是木星之日
what you call, we call it guru, is the day of the guru,
你們所稱呼的，我們稱為導師日，
is the Jupiter, is the teacher.
就是木星，代表老師。
Now, Friday is the day of the Goddess.
而星期五則是女神之日。
Now see the chakras also, of the Goddess,
現在看看脈輪，女神的脈輪，
Mother of the Earth, Mother of the Universe,
大地之母，宇宙之母，
Venus.
金星。
But in Indian Sanskrit language the names of the days
但在印度梵語中，這些日子的名稱
are exactly the same, tallying with the stars,
與星體完全一致
Then Saturday is the day of Shri Krishna, Shani, is Saturn.
那麼星期六是克里希那的日子，也是土星日（Shani）。
Then Sunday is the day of Christ, the Sun.
而星期日則是基督日，也是太陽的日子。
Monday is the day of Sadashiva,
星期一是全能主（Sadashiva）的日子，
is of realization, of integration.
象徵自覺和整合。
These are the seven days when God created the whole universe.
這七天是上帝創造整個宇宙的日子。
That’s what I told yesterday, that in this narrow way
我昨天就說過，用狹隘的視角，
you cannot understand Christianity.
基督教是無法理解的。
You’ll think it’s all mad, which is not.
你會覺得這一切都是瘋話，但其實並非如此。
Only when you read other things, other scriptures,
只有當你閱讀其他書籍、其他經文時，
then only you will understand what Christ said.
你才能真正理解基督所言。
So today is the day of – first day –
今天是象神格泥沙
of when Ganesha was created,
誕生的日子──第一天
in the sense that, though today is not a Tuesday,
雖然今天不是星期二，
but according to dates of the moon,
但根據月相，
today is the day, first day of the moon in this month.
今天是這個月的第一天。
[Marathi]
[馬拉地語]
Chaitra. We call it Chaitra. Chaitra is the month.
我們稱之為柴特拉月（Chaitra）。柴特拉月就是這個月。
And this is the time when –
而這段時間正是——
[Marathi]
[馬拉地語]
Gauri is the Chaitra.
哥維女神（Gauri）在柴特拉月（Chaitra）期間誕生。
So the establishment of the Gauri
因此，哥維女神的誕生
is taken place during these nine days.
就在這九天裡。
But Ganesha has to be established before anything else.
但格泥沙必須先於其他一切誕生。
Though first Gauri had to come,
雖然哥維女神必須先出現，
you can see that. Gauri had to come first to establish Ganesha.
這一點顯而易見。哥維女神必須先出現格泥沙才能誕生。
But Ganesha is always put before even Gauri.
但格泥沙總是被放在哥維女神之前。
Before the pujana of the, worship of the Ganesha,
在對格泥沙進行崇拜之前，
nothing starts;
一切都無法開始；
because He’s the one who takes out all the obstacles,
因為祂會消除所有的障礙、
all the negativities,
所有的負面因素、
all the hurdles that are going to come up,
所有即將出現的困難，
all the attentions that are here and there.
以及所有紛擾。
So that’s why we first worship Ganesha,
所以，這就是為什麼我們先崇拜格泥沙，
just to ask Him to protect us.
只為祈求祂的庇佑
But first the Gauri has to come,
但首先哥維女神必須降臨，
and that’s how the Gauri is this nine days.
這就是哥維女神在這九天裡顯現的方式。
She came on this Earth to fight the devils and demons,
她來到人間是為了對抗魔鬼、惡魔
negativity, for people to transcend
和所有負面，
the Bhavasagara, the Void,
幫助人們超越幻海（Bhavasagara），
the maya, the illusion.
即虛空、幻象（maya）。
When they were praying, when they were doing anything,
過去，當人們祈禱或做任何事時，
people used to obstruct
總會有羅剎（rakshasas）阻撓，
and then they troubled the bhaktas, the devotees of God.
給神的信徒帶來困擾。
Rakshasas, in those days the rakshasas were separate
那時，羅剎和聖人
and the saints were separate;
是涇渭分明的，
there was not such a mixture as it is today.
沒有像今天這樣混雜的情況。
We find in saints there are negativities sitting there.
我們發現，賢人身上也潛藏著負面能量。
Was never so before. This is Kali Yuga.
以前從未如此。這是爭鬥時代。（Kali Yuga）。
It’s such a confusion that there is no absolute saint
如今的混亂之處在於，既沒有絕對的聖人，
or there’s no absolute rakshasas.
亦無絕對羅剎。
These rakshasas have come and sitting in our heads.
這些羅剎已經潛入我們的頭腦，盤踞其中。
They are within us, so the negativity is there,
它們存在於我們內心，所以負面能量就在那裏，
so we are not absolute saints.
因此我們並非絕對的聖人。
And this is the big problem of Sahaja Yoga is, that
這也是霎哈嘉瑜伽的一大問題，
even when you are worshipping Me,
即使當你們崇拜我，
try to be more on the saints than on the negative side.
也要努力更多地向聖人靠攏，而非負面能量。
Try to be more on the saintly side.
努力更多地神聖靠攏。
Because you are saints, no doubt,
因為你們無疑是聖人，
but these horrible things have somehow or other
但這些可怕的東西不知何故
gone into your heads and they are sitting in
進入了你們的頭腦，
your superego and ego, these horrible negativities,
它們盤踞在你們的超我和自我之中，這些可怕的負面能量，
which you must really decide today to throw them away.
你們今天必須下定決心將它們徹底拋棄。
Because you are really saints and these are the bad spots,
因為你們都是真正的聖人，而這些污點──
kalanka.
卡拉卡。
Is the thing that really ruins you, is within you.
才是真正毀掉你們的東西，它就在你們內心深處。
So try to throw it away; try to become positive,
所以，試著擺脫它；試著變得正面，
be one with the puja.
與崇拜融為一體。
The second thing is the importance of this day is,
第二個重點點是，今天之所以重要，
that I have never celebrated this first day anywhere, so far.
是因為我至今為止從未在任何地方慶祝過這個節日的第一天。
It was to be in Australia.
原本計劃在澳洲慶祝的。
It is the right of Australia to have this day here,
澳洲有權在這裡慶祝
celebrated here.
這個節日。
We had other pujas, other Navaratris we had;
我們之前也舉行過其他的崇拜，慶祝過其他的九夜節；
with that I celebrated the first, second, third,
我慶祝過九夜節的第一天、第二天、第三天，
over nine days we have done.
總共持續了九天。
But never this Navaratri as such
但是，我們從未在任何地方慶祝過這個九夜節的第一天，
we have celebrated this day anywhere, of the Shalivahana.
也就是沙利瓦漢節。
Though in London they had a little sort of a thing on this, which I,
雖然在倫敦，他們也舉辦過類似的活動，
we had on the seventh of April, then I spoke about it;
我們在4月7日也舉辦過，當時我也談到了；
but actually on this day we had no puja, before.
但實際上在這一天，我們之前並沒有舉行過任何崇拜。
So, this is very creditable that it should happen here.
所以，今天能在這裡慶祝，真是太好了。
I’m very happy, because this is where Gauri established Shri Ganesh.
我十分高興，因為這裡正是哥維女神建立格泥沙的地方。
Now for today we have two things to be worshipped:
今天我們要敬拜兩個神祈：
one, Ganesha, because Ganesha can preserve our status,
一是象神格泥沙，
our heights,
因為格泥沙能守護
in our realization.
我們在自覺的地位和境界。
He protects us when we are getting our realization,
當我們得自覺時、升進時，祂庇佑我們；
we are rising high;
保護我們。祂照顧我們，
so He preserves and He protects.
因此祂保守並保護我們。
And He looks after us and gives us wisdom,
賜給我們智慧，
to have our ascent in such a way
使我們的升進之路，
that we do not deviate into the left and the right side;
不傾向左脈；也不傾向右脈，
we have full dignity;
保持尊嚴，
and that we are fully integrated with our heart,
與我們的內心、與濕婆真諦
with Shiva Tattwa, with our realization,
與我們的自覺完全合一，
and do it with our heart genuinely.
並讓我們由內裡真誠。
That’s why we worship Shri Ganesh.
這就是我們敬拜格泥沙的原因。
But today is actually the puja of the Gauri,
但今天其實是哥維女神
that is, the Kundalini.
（即昆達里尼）的崇拜。
So Shri Ganesh we’ll do first of all,
所以我們先會崇拜格泥沙，
and then we’ll worship the Kundalini, which is the Gauri.
然後再崇拜昆達里尼，也就是哥維女神。
Now luckily I got a sari: this is really remarkable,
剛好我有一件紗麗：這真是太神奇了，
because this is the color of Australia.
因為這正是澳洲的代表色。
Green is the color of the Gauri. Gauri wears the green sari.
綠色是哥維女神的顏色。哥維女神身著綠色紗麗。
And there is also – this is the, this is the,
還有──這是，這是，
this is the symbol of Gauri only.
這是哥維的象徵。
This is the symbol of Gauri, and this one inside is the Ganesha,
這是哥維的象徵。而裡面的這個是格泥沙，
is in that color, is most surprising this sari I got.
也是這個顏色——我得到的這件紗麗真是太令人驚喜了。
So this one also is just the other way round,
所以這件紗麗的顏色正好相反——
more of Ganesha color and less of the Gauri color.
格泥沙的顏色更多，哥維的顏色更少。
This is a very traditional combination
這是印度色彩搭配中非常傳統的組合，
in the Indian color scheme, because red is the color of Ganesha.
因為紅色是格泥沙的顏色。
In you people it is very red and it can become more crimson,
在你們內裡，紅色非常紅，可以變得更深紅，
can become absolutely black,
甚至可以轉變成純黑色，
can be absolutely reduced to nothing.
最終可能完全消逝。
But in Me it is the color of this clay,
但對我來說，它是陶土的顏色，
because it’s absolutely obedient, it’s absolutely one with Me,
因為祂完全順從，祂與我完全合一，
so it’s the color of the clay. And the Gauri is the Mother Earth.
所以祂是陶土的顏色。哥維就是大地母親。
That’s the place where the Gauri exists, in the Mother Earth;
哥維存在於大地母親之中；
and that’s why the color is green
這就是為什麼顏色是綠色
because Mother Earth is always covered with green,
因為大地母親總是被綠色覆蓋
at least She’s covered with.
至少她是被綠色覆蓋的。
And Ganesha’s color is that of the clay
而格泥沙的顏色是陶土的顏色，
because He’s made out of the Mother Earth,
因為祂是由大地母親所創造，
element is the Mother Earth.
祂的元素就是大地母親。
I hope I have been able to explain to you the symbolic relationship.
希望我已經能向你們解釋這象徵性的關聯。
Do you know the story how Ganesha was created by Gauri?
你們知道哥維創造格泥沙的故事嗎？
So that I will tell you; and then we all can have.
讓我來告訴你，這樣大家都能明白。
It’s very interesting, that’s why I said I’ll have My bath here.
這非常有趣，所以我才說我要在這裡沐浴。
It is said this ….
當時…
[Excuse me, Mother, we can’t hear very well down the back.]
[抱歉，母親，我們在後面聽不太清楚。]
[Is there any way You can speak louder or that we can hear better?]
[有沒有辦法您說話大聲點，或是我們能聽得更清楚？]
What’s she say?
她說什麼？
[They cannot hear.]
[他們聽不見。]
You can’t hear Me?e …]
你們聽不見我嗎？e …]
[Yogini: No, Mother.]
[瑜伽修行者：不，母親。]
All right, so I’ll have to shout.
好的，那我得大聲喊了。
Not at all?
完全沒有嗎？
[Yogini: Yes, a little, most of the time...]
[瑜伽修行者：是的，有一點，大多數時候...]
All right. Should I use this?
好的。我該用這個嗎？
All right. This you can hear.
好的。這個你聽得到。
So I’m now going to tell you
那麼我現在要告訴你
the story of Shri Ganesha’s birth.
關於象神格涅沙誕生的故事。
Is very interesting, it’s very symbolic. This is Christ, and that is,
非常有趣，極具象徵意義。祂就是基督，也就是說，
He is the Omega and He is the Alpha and all that they talk of,
祂是歐米茄，祂是阿爾法，祂是人們所談論的一切，
they don’t know what they are talking.
他們不知道他們在說什麼。
There’s so short form of what the whole thing is.
整個事情的形成很簡短。
They don’t know Ganesha at all, nothing.
他們根本不瞭解格涅沙的由來，什麼都不知道。
They just take one word here and there, just talk like that.
他們只是東拼西湊抓幾個詞，就這樣隨口說說。
So He’s the first one created.
要明白祂是第一個被創作的。
Now it’s very symbolic:
現在這非常具有象徵意義：
the pure power
哥維女神象徵著
of desire to be one with the spirit is symbolized in the Gauri.
渴望與靈連結合一
The primordial Gauri is that power
的純粹力量。
which has separated from Her Lord,
我們可以說，哥維女神
we can say.
即是與她的主分離的力量。
In Her previous lives She was separated,
在她的前世，祂們被分開了，
and again She’s born as Parvati.
而今她再次降生為帕娃蒂。
And She wants to be one with Shiva, which is the Spirit.
她想與全能主合而為一，全能主就是靈。
So now the marriage has taken place,
現在結婚儀式已經完成了，
in the sense that now She can meet Him.
從某種意義上說，現在她可以見她的夫君全能主了。
The wedding kindling has to start.
婚禮的火種必須開始點燃。
But She’s not yet married,
但她尚未完婚，
in the sense that She’s still a Virgin,
在某種意義上，她仍是聖女處女，
but married otherwise – means She is now about to rise.
雖然她已經結婚了—這代表她現在即將升起。
Before that She wants to have a bath,
在此之前，她想先沐浴淨身，
because She has to meet Her Lord.
因為她必須去見她的夫君。
So She must have Her bath, the bridal bath.
所以她必須做她的淨身沐浴，那新娘的浴禮。
She’s a virgin, absolutely virgin, and She goes for Her bath.
她是女神，絕對的處女，她正在進行她的淨身沐浴。
Now, She’s afraid that anybody might come inside
現在，她擔心可能會有人闖進來
when She’s having Her bath.
當她正在沐浴的時候。
Look at the delicacy of the whole thing:
看看整件事件的精微處：
this desire, which just is meant for the spirit,
純潔的願望是為了與靈合一，
doesn’t want to be exposed to anything else,
不希望碰觸到任何不潔，
any negativity coming in, anything happening like that.
不想接觸任何負能量，任何類似的事情。
So She closes the door,
於是她關上門，
but still She’s worried from the back side somebody may come.
但她仍擔心會有人從後面進來。
So She puts this scented powder, which we use in India,
所以她撒了這種我們印度使用的香粉，
for the bride specially it is the right one,
這是特別為新娘準備的正統香粉。
and rubs Her body with that, and She finds
她用這個擦拭身體，發現
that a lot of it comes out. So She makes the Ganesha out of that,
很多香粉從她身上流下來。所以她用這些香粉捏作了格涅沙，
now imagine how much vibrated it must be.
現在想像一下格涅沙會具有多大的生命能量。
She puts that – is made of camphor
這香粉，是由樟腦
and all these beautiful things which are really celestial –
和所有非常神聖的物品製成，—
and that is completely vibrated on Her body.
且具有她身體上完全的生命能量。
She makes a Ganesha and puts Him to the back of the bathroom;
由此她做了格涅沙，把他放在浴室的後面;
She’s having Her bath nicely.
於是她很安心地進行沐浴。
At that time Shiva comes suddenly, knocks at the door.
這時，全能主突然來了，敲了敲門。
She doesn’t hear Him.
她沒有聽見祂。
So He goes from the back door. There He sees Shri Ganesha sitting.
於是祂從後門進入。在那裏祂看見格涅沙正坐著。
He asks Shri Ganesha, “Who are You?”
祂問格涅沙：「你是誰？」
So He says, “I am the Son of Gauri.”
祂說：「我是哥維女神的孩子。」
Shiva can’t understand; She is a Virgin
全之主無法理解; 祂知道哥維是處女之身
and this one is saying, “I am the Son of the Gauri.”
而這個孩童卻說， “我是她的孩子” 。
See now the Immaculate Conception,
現在看看聖靈感孕的概念，
try to understand.
試著理解。
So Shiva says, “How can She have a child? She is the Virgin.”
所以全能主說：「她怎麼會有孩子呢？她是處女。
And He thinks [She’s] He’s bringing slander on His wife who is a Virgin.
他認為這孩子試圖玷污他妻子的聖名。
So He cuts His neck in anger,
於是他他立刻憤怒地拔劍將孩子斬首，
and He enters into the bathroom.
然後走進了浴室。
And Gauri is ready to receive Him.
哥維已經準備好迎接他了。
And She looks out and She sees Her child is dead.
她向外望去，發現她的孩子被丈夫所殺。
So He asked Her, “What is this?”
於是她問：“發生什麼事？”
Said, “That’s My child I created out of My, this mala” –
並說：「那是我的孩子，我用身上的塵土創造的」——
what you call this, all the body things that came out –
你稱之為這個，所有身體的塵土—
“I’ve created Him, and I have put Him down there.
「我創造了他，我把他放在那。
How dare You kill Him?”
你怎麼能殺他？ 她說
She said, “ Now what to do?”
他說：「現在該怎麼辦？
He said, “All right, what You do is to go
她說：「好吧，你要做的就是去找
and find the head of any animal that is available,
任何可用的動物的頭，
and we will put that on this trunk
我們會把它移植到這個孩子的身上，
and He’ll be My son again.”
他就會再次復活成為我的兒子。
Now it’s all prearranged;
現在這一切都是預先安排好的;
because this child was not to grow into
因為這個孩子不會長大成為
a human ego and superego business.
一個擁有自我和超我的人類。
It had to be the embodiment of childhood,
祂必須是純潔孩童的化身，
embodiment of childlike innocence,
像孩子般的純真的化身，
because He’s the embodiment of innocence.
因為祂是純真的化身。
So they had to get the head of an animal.
所以他們必須用動物的頭來呈現。
Now the wisest animal on this Earth is elephant,
地球上最聰明的動物是大象，
and elephant was saved in evolution in a very miraculous way,
大象在演化過程奇蹟般存活下來，
is also another description which I’ll give you later on.
這部分我會稍後再詳細解釋。
So a she-elephant, mother elephant
所以一頭母象、大象媽媽
was lying down with her back towards her child,
她背對著孩子躺下，
that’s why in India women never sleep with their back
這就是為什麼在印度，女性從不會背對著孩子睡覺，
towards their children, never.
絕對不會。
The child has to be in front, pudhe, in front.
孩子必須在前方，放在母親前方。
It should never be put at the back of the mother, never.
他永遠不會在母親的背後，絕對不行。
Mother will get up and go on the other side and change the sides,
母親會站起來走到另一邊，換個位置，
but she would never put the child at the back.
她永遠不會把孩子放在後面。
So the head of that little animal was cut,
於是那隻小象的頭被割下，
and He brought it and was put for Shri Ganesh.
將它拿來，放到錫呂·格涅沙的身體上。
And that’s how Shri Ganesha was created.
這就是 象神的由來。
But you know, elephant is the conveyance of Mahalakshmi.
但你知道嗎，大象其實是摩訶拉克希米(中脈女神)的坐騎。
So the body is from Mahakali,
所以身體來自摩訶迦利(左脈女神)，
but the head is given by Mahalakshmi, the evolutionary power.
但頭部是由中脈的進化力量摩訶拉希什米賜予的。
Now this Ganesha within us resides
在創造祂之後，哥維任命錫呂·格涅沙為根輪之神，
in the Mooladhara Chakra.
祂駐在我們內裡的根輪。我們內在的格涅沙駐在根輪。
Some people who tried all kinds of tricks to find God
有些人試了各種方法來尋找神，
must have seen the trunk of Shri Ganesha,
他們可能看到了象神的象鼻，
and must have thought this is the kundalini,
於是誤以為那就是靈量（昆達里尼），
because as a Mother I give them few marks for that,
身為母親，我對此只能給他們打幾分——
and that’s how they started all these perversions
這就是他們開始對格涅沙產生
and wrong things about Ganesha.
各種歪曲和錯誤觀念的原因。
But He is embodiment of innocence,
祂是純真的化身，
and later on you must read in “Devi Bhagwat”
往後你必須閱讀《女神往世書》，
how He incarnated on this Earth as Christ;
瞭解祂如何以基督之姿降臨人間；
and how He is going to come with His eleven powers
以及祂如何帶著十一種神力
on this Earth as Kalki.
降臨這世間成為迦奇(Kalki)。
It is very difficult for Hindus to accept that Ganesha,
對印度教徒來說，很難接受像祂這樣
such a dynamic personality like Him,
充滿活力的人物──格涅沙
should become a person like Christ, who got Himself crucified.
竟然會成為基督而被釘在十字架上。
And it is impossible,
這簡直不可思議──
at least Hindus have much wider knowledge
至少印度教徒擁有更廣闊的知識
and much wider sense, but it is impossible for ardent Christians
和更寬廣的見識，但對熱忱的基督徒來說是不可能
to understand that Christ could be this elephant boy.
明白基督即是格涅沙。
That is beyond them, because for them Christ should be a man
這絕對超出了他們的理解範圍，在他們看來，基督應該是一個
who has no power to kill anyone.
沒有毀滅能力的人。
And then they say that He’s coming to kill us,
然後他們又說祂要來殺我們，
I don’t know how they manage these things.
我不知道他們是怎麼想的。
They catch hold of one thing,
他們抓住一點，
like He was the Omega and Alpha, finished;
就是祂是歐米伽和阿爾法，一切都這樣完成了；
now how are they authorized, God knows?
至於他們哪來的授權，天曉得？
But whatever it is, they do not see the other things,
但無論如何，基督徒看不到其他的事—
that He had a Mother; He said about the Holy Spirit.
祂有一位母親；祂談到了聖靈。
He said it in such a good way,
祂用如此美好的方式述說，
that “I’ll be sending Holy Spirit.” And also He said
「我將差遣聖靈。」並且祂還說
that “Those who are,
那些是，
those who have sinned against Me or have insulted Me,
那些得罪我或侮辱我的人，
it’s all right, but with the Holy Spirit nothing will be tolerated”,
都沒關係，但絕不容忍任何反對聖靈的行為”
very clearly. Why did He say so?
祂說得非常清楚。 祂為什麼這麼說？
He’s Alpha and Omega, but why did He say so?
祂是阿爾法和歐米茄，祂為什麼這麼說呢？
Of course, He’s the first who was created,
當然，祂是第一個被創造的，
and at this stage, at Kalki stage also it is He who,
在太初階段，在迦奇階段，祂也在那裡，
He’s there at the end of it, no doubt.
祂毫無疑問地存有到最後。
But that doesn’t mean because you are Christians
但這並不代表因為你們是基督徒
you have a special right.
你們就擁有特權。
Not at all. On the contrary, I would say many Hindus
完全不是。相反地，我認為許多印度教徒，
have much more right on Ganesha than you have,
比你們更有資格崇拜格涅沙。
because you have spoilt your innocence.
因為你們已經失去了純真。
They have not spoilt their innocence.
他們還沒有失去純真。
So though you may call yourself Christians,
所以儘管你可以自稱基督徒，
Christians and fight for Christ, but you are not;
基督徒並為基督而戰，但你們並非真正的基督徒；
because the basics of Christ is innocence,
因為基督的本質是純真，
which we have ruined.
而我們已將其破壞。
So those who – also Sahaja yogis – get identified
因此那些——包括霎哈嘉瑜伽士——認同
with Christ must know that this identification is actually
基督的人必須明白，這種認同實際上是
a conditioning;
制約，
it is not factually so. If so, you have to become innocent.
事實並非如此。因此，你們必須重拾純真，
You must re-establish your innocence.
你必須重建自己的純真。
Then you are really Christians, and then you are really so.
這樣你才是真正的基督徒，這樣你才真正算是如此。
And I would say people in India – as it is, you know,
我要說，印度人——就像你知道的，
luckily we did not get advanced as you people got.
幸好我們沒有像你們那樣發展得那麼先進。
We never fall into the traps of advancement, luckily:
幸運的是，我們從未落入過度發展的陷阱：
too sluggish, elephant-like people,
我們就像是行動遲緩、像大象一樣的民族，
we could not fall into anything.
所以什麼都跌不進去。
India is like, large like an elephant.
印度就像是一頭巨大的大象
Anything comes in, this just goes on throwing this side,
不管什麼進來，都會被它擋在一邊，
that side, that doesn’t accept anything.
擋在另一邊，什麼都不接受
We never bothered about Freud. For us he’s some sort of
我們從不在意佛洛伊德。對我們來說，他就是那種
a legendary fellow living in fool’s paradise,
住在於愚人天堂裡的傳奇傢伙，
we never accepted him.
我們從未接受過他。
Nothing can penetrate that elephantine thing.
沒有任何東西能穿透那頭大象的思維。
You see, it just goes on blowing off all the things that comes round,
你瞧，它會把所有來來往往的東西吹走，
so nothing got into their heads.
沒任何東西能進他們的腦。
They never spoiled their innocence,
他們從未失去純真，
simply because they are too large and very lethargic
因為他們體型太大，
to new ideas.
對新思想極為遲鈍。
And that’s how they have, despite everything
正因如此，儘管歷經種種困難
they are not converted Christians,
他們從未皈依基督教，
they never heard of Christ, some of them.
有些人甚至從未聽聞過基督。
They have maintained their innocence much more
他們之所以能保持如此純真
and their sincerity of their heart,
和真誠，
because they are not disconnected.
是因為他們沒有脫離連結。
When Ganesha is destroyed you get disconnected.
一旦格涅沙的形像被摧毀，人就會脫離實相。
Your heart works on one side, your brain works on another side.
你的心和你的大腦各自運作。
So, that they have not been able to yet achieve,
他們至今從沒達到那種分離的狀態。
that kind of a dissociation. And whatever they may try,
無論他們如何嘗試，
they know in their – that it is wrong.
他們心底明白——這是錯誤的。
They may try, I mean, like people steal
他們可能會嘗試，我是說，就像人們偷東西一樣
but they know it is wrong; in the same way they still know.
但他們知道這是錯的；他們仍然明白這一點。
So for us, we must know that we have to achieve
所以對我們來說，我們必須明白自己必須
our position as innocent people.
保持純真的狀態。
But your Mother is very gracious,
你的母親非常仁慈,
She’s very powerful, She’s very loving,
祂非常強大, 也非常慈愛,
and She has created you on the same pattern as Ganesha.
而且祂是按照格涅沙的模式創造了你。
You have all the powers that Shri Ganesha has.
你擁有所有格涅沙所有的力量。
The greatest power that Shri Ganesha has,
格涅沙擁有的至高神力，
that you can come so close to Me.
就是你能如此接近我。
No other gods can come that close to Me as you can come.
沒有其他神祈能像你一樣接近我。
Kundalini cannot be risen by any gods, any incarnations
昆達里尼只能由格涅沙喚醒。
but Shri Ganesha.
他必須引導昆達里尼，
He has to inform the kundalini, otherwise kundalini cannot rise.
否則靈量無法升起。
And it is you who have the power to raise the kundalini
而你們擁有提升靈量的力量
on your fingers. How many powers I have given you.
就在你們指尖。我已賜予你們多少力量啊。
you have no idea at all.
你根本無法想像。
I have made you in the pattern of Shri Ganesh.
我按照格涅沙的模式創造了你。
So you have to establish that innocence within you;
因此你必須在自己內心建立起那份純真；
that is being also established.
這也正在逐步建立中。
You’ll get back your innocence.
你將重獲純真。
But the second thing which is so important about Shri Ganesh
關於格涅沙，第二件至關重要的事是，
one has to learn, that
你必須了解
He does not know any other god but His Mother.
祂除了祂的母親帕爾瓦蒂之外，不認識任何其他神明。
For Him nothing exists but His Mother.
對祂而言，除了祂的母親，別無其他。
He’s so dedicated.
祂是如此虔誠。
There’s a story once when Parvati,
曾經有這樣一個故事：
His Mother gave –
祂的母親帕爾瓦蒂對祂說：
said that “I will give You a big present,
「我會送給你們一份大禮，
that there should be competition between You two brothers.”
你們兄弟二人比賽。」
Second was the Kartikeya, the one, another brother of His
第二個是卡提凱亞，祂的另一個兄弟，
who came on this Earth just to destroy this Narakasura.
降世人間就是為了消滅那羅迦蘇羅。
Is the, all the destructive powers
所有毀滅的力量都匯聚
were combined to create Kartikeya.
來創造卡提凱亞。
So She said, “Whosoever goes round this Earth,
於是她說：「誰先繞地球一圈，
I’ll give You a prize.”
我將賜予獎賞。」
So, the conveyance of
於是，這樣的比賽方式
Kartikeya is such a fast one, is a peacock.
卡提凱亞的坐騎是孔雀，速度極快。
So He got onto His peacock, started flying out like an aeroplane.
所以祂就騎上孔雀，像飛機一樣飛出去。
And Shri Ganesha’s conveyance is just a little mouse,
而格涅沙的座騎只是一隻小老鼠,
so what should He do? He took to wisdom.
那他該怎麼做？他求取智慧。
He said, “Who can be greater than My Mother?
他說：「有誰能比我母親更偉大？」
She has created all the gods.
她創造了所有的神明。
She’s the Mahakali, She’s the Adi Shakti.
她是摩訶迦利，她是太初力量。
She has created all the gods, She has created all the universes,
她創造了所有的神靈，她創造了所有的宇宙，
She’s the one who has done everything, who can be greater than Her?
她是一切的主宰，誰能比她更偉大？
She’s the greatest of all.” So she just, He just went round Her
她是萬物中最偉大的。」於是他，他只是繞著她走了
only thrice and He got the prize.
僅僅三圈，就獲得了獎賞。
And still He was flying in the air, Kartikeya.
卡提凱亞仍在空中飛行。
He fought even Shiva.
格泥沙甚至與全能主爭吵，
He fought everyone.
他與所有人吵架。
It’s a very interesting story how all that happened,
這一切如何發生的，是個非常有趣的故事。
that shows complete dedication.
這也展現了對母親完全的奉獻。
And for Sahaja yogis
而對於霎哈嘉瑜伽士來說
it is important to understand complete surrendering, dedication,
非常重要的是，要完全理解臣服、
and also a genuine feeling from the heart.
奉獻以及發自內心的真誠情感。
I will ask Raul Bai sometimes to talk to you about the protocol,
我會請勞爾·拜跟你們談禮節
that’s important, though I am so close.
——這很重要，儘管我與你們如此親近。
Even Christ would not say anything;
連基督也不會說什麼；
sometimes the way you people talk to Me, I am amazed.
但有時你們跟我說的話，讓我感到驚訝。
Certain things you say to Me, I’m amazed:
你們對我說話的方式，讓我感到訝異：
how can you say these things to Me, knowingly what I am?
明白我的身分，你們怎麼會這麼跟我說話？
But you forget.
但你卻忘記了。
So it is important to understand that they were great
所以理解他們很偉大是很重要的
because they knew the greatness of their Mother.
因為他們深知母親的偉大。
In the same way, you all have to learn certain protocols
同樣地，你們都必須學習特定的規範
which Raul Bai will teach you,
勞爾·拜會教你們禮儀，
so that you do not make any mistakes
這樣才不會犯下任何錯誤
of saying things which are not proper.
說出不恰當的話。
It comes from bad Vishuddhi, no doubt,
這無疑來自於不潔淨的喉輪，
but consciously if you work it out
但如果你有意識地去調整
you will do good to yourself; because you know,
對自己有所助益；你知道的，
anything against the Holy Spirit won’t be tolerated,
任何違背聖靈的行為都不會被容忍，
anything, can you believe it?
任何事，你能相信嗎？
What strong words these are! Just think of it,
這些話語多麼強烈！試想一下，
anything against the Holy Spirit.
任何違背聖靈的行為。
So one has to understand the protocol, for Sahaja yogis,
所以每一個人都必須了解這些規則，對於霎哈嘉瑜伽士來說，
for Sahaja yogis, don’t talk against the Holy Spirit.
對於霎哈嘉瑜伽士，不要違背聖靈的旨意。
But the protocol is there which one must understand,
但這個法則確實存在，每個人都必須明白，
and how far to go, how far to understand
甚麼可以說、可以做，
is very, very, absolutely rudimentary for Sahaja Yoga.
對於霎哈嘉瑜伽來說，這是非常、非常、絕對基礎的。
So today we have a great day
所以今天我們有個偉大的日子
of Shri Ganesha’s Mother being established, incarnated.
是建立格涅沙母親，祂降世的日子。
Today is the day She had Her bath, we can say,
今天可以說是她沐浴淨身的吉祥日
and that’s why I said I’ll come and have a bath here.
這就是為什麼我說我會來這裡沐浴。
About the times and timings,
關於時間和時機，
one should know that Mother knows best,
應該要知道母親最清楚，
and everything works out with the timing properly.
而且在適當的時機一切都會準時進行。
Because the, you know you are, you are ahead of India,
因為，你知道的，澳洲時間領先印度，
and all the timings work out in that way.
所有的時間安排都是這樣運作的。
So everything has to work in the way,
所以一切都要按照這個方式運作，
actually the timings are of the moon,
實際上這些時間都是依照月亮的運行來安排的，
so you don’t have to worry about what is the timing,
所以你不用擔心時間點的問題，
what time this works out, this thing, that.
不必擔心這件事、那件事的時間安排。
The watches and all that, in Sahaja Yoga,
在霎哈嘉瑜伽裡，手錶等等一切，
work out according to My understanding.
都要按照我的理解來運作。
So one has to relax and just enjoy the puja.
所以只要放鬆並享受崇拜就好。
I think today you are going to receive lots of vibrations.
我想今天你們會接收到很多生命能量。
Just enjoy them, just enjoy them.
好好享受它們，只管享受就對了。
And if your ego is there or anything,
如果你的自我還在或有任何雜念，
just ask them to shut up, that’s all.
直接叫他們閉嘴就好了。
All right?
好嗎？
Now, so first we’ll have Ganesha Puja,
首先，我們要進行格涅沙崇拜，
as Modi will be doing,
莫迪會主持，
and he will be explaining what is to be done.
他會說明該怎麼做。
How Ganesha is pleased with small, small things you will see now.
你會看到格涅沙是如何因微小的細節而歡喜。